Sir, could you step to the door?
先生，走到門口來？
- Yeah. - Sir, we received a 911 call.
- 怎麼了 - 我們收到911報警
Is everything okay?
沒事吧？
My wife was upset. She might have called.
我妻子有點不高興，可能是她打的
- Everything's fine now. - Sir, could you open the door?
- 現在沒事了 - 請把門開一下？
What's your name, sir?
你的姓名，先生？
It's Porter. Rip Porter.
波特，理普·波特
Mr. Porter, could you step inside?
波特先生，能不能走進去？
Go ahead and have a seat, sir.
請坐下，先生
Mr. Porter, is your wife here?
波特先生，你妻子在麼？
I don't know. She might be upstairs.
不知道，可能在樓上
Wen. Wendy!
溫，溫蒂？
Mrs. Porter? Police.
波特太太？我是警察
Wendy?
溫蒂？
Mrs. Porter.
波特太太
Ma'am, are you all right?
女士，你沒事吧？
- Wen! - Stop resisting, sir.
- 溫？ - 別掙扎了，先生
Get off! Get off!
放手！放手！
Wendy.
溫蒂
Ah.
啊
Just to the right over there.
就在那邊靠右
There you go. Perfect.
就這樣，很好
See, you want to go right down the middle of this channel.
保持在這條水道的中間
Can I drive by myself, Daddy?
我能自己開麼，爸爸？
You can drive when we get outside of the marina. Okay, bud?
開出港灣後你就自己開，行麼，夥計？
- Hey, Daddy? - Yep.
- 爸爸？ - 嗯
Am I just a rookie at this?
我是菜鳥麼？
What'd you say? A rookie?
你說什麼？菜鳥？
- That's a big boat, huh? - Oh, yeah.
- 那是艘大船，嗯？ - 噢，是啊
It's, like, 200feet.
好像有200英尺長
Think we're gonna see any fish?
我們會看到魚嗎？
I could give you a mask, throw you in the water. You'd see plenty of fish.
給你戴個面罩，把你扔水堙A你能看到很多魚
- You having fun? - Yeah.
- 好玩麼？ - 好玩
I love you, boy.
我愛你，兒子
Hey, Joey. Should I sing Mommy a tune? Yeah?
喬伊，我給媽咪唱首歌怎麼樣？
Yes, please sing a tune, sweetheart.
是的，唱一首吧，親愛的
# Molly #
# 莫莉 #
How's that for an intro?
這開頭不錯吧？
It'd be good if you knew a few more chords.
再多幾個和弦就更好了
Look, Mommy.
瞧，媽咪
What is this? Is this your story?
是什麼？你的故事？
Yep.
是的
Sweetie, this is beautiful.
寶貝，很漂亮
Will you help me with the words?
幫我寫幾個字，好麼？
Um, of course, but not right now because it's time for bed.
當然，不過不是現在，因為你該睡覺了
But I have to finish my story.
我的故事要寫完啊
Nice try, kiddo. Go to bed. Listen to your mama.
行了，孩子，聽你媽的睡覺吧
Tomorrow, you can finish your story.
明天，你可以寫完你的故事
Right now it is 7:00, and you haven't even had a bath yet.
現在七點了，你還沒洗澡
Get Mr. Growls.
拿上格勞斯先生
- Will you sing a song first? - A song?
- 你能先唱首歌嗎？ - 唱歌？
- Daddy, don't do it. - Joey.
- 爸爸，別唱 - 喬伊
- Don't do it, Daddy. - This is a little song I wrote for you about bedtime.
- 別唱，爸爸 - 這是一首你該睡覺了的歌
Oh, no! He did it!
噢，不，他唱了
# Joey, Joey, Joey better get his butt to bed #
# 喬伊，喬伊，喬伊，你最好現在就上床 #
# Or Daddy, Daddy, Daddy's gonna drop him on his head #
# 不然老爸，老爸，老爸把他倒過來扔出去 #
- # Come on # - Whoa, Daddy.
- # 來吧 # - 哇哦，爸爸
Kiss your son good night.
親你兒子晚安
- Good night, Daddy. - Good night. Night, Mama.
- 晚安，爸爸 - 晚安。晚安，媽咪
- See you in a second. - Okay. You win.
- 一會見 - 好吧，你贏了
That's right, Son. Daddy always wins.
說對了，兒子，老爸總是贏
I just want you to know...
我只想讓你知道…
You did the right thing.
你做的是對的
Okay?
好麼？
# I was making a living#
# 我在謀生 #
Okay.
好
# And I forgot to live#
# 卻忘記了生活 #
# I've lost you forever#
# 我永遠失去了你 #
Father Logan, when I was leaving today-
洛根神父，我今天出來的時候
He wrote down his number, and...
他寫下了他的號碼…
He said we can call him anytime we need him if we need anything.
他說我們有需要隨時可以找他
So, I just want- I want you to- I want you to take that.
所以，我要你…我要你…要你拿著它
I want you to- I want you to hold on to it.
我要你…我要你拿好它
And if, you know, we need to call him...
如果，你知道，如果我們需要…
You just give it to me-
你給我…
and I'll call him.
我會找他的
That okay?
好嗎？
Okay.
好
Last night was so terrifying.
昨晚我很惶恐
I was afraid that I would come out...
我擔心我出來了…
And... you wouldn't be there...
但是…你不在…
That I'd be alone, you know.
就我一個人，知道麼
Oh, baby.
噢，寶貝
I told you I'd be there.
我說過我會來的
Thank you.
謝謝你
- I love this. - Yeah?
- 我喜歡這髮型 - 真的？
- Little greasy. - No.
- 有點油 - 不
Is there anything you- anyplace you want to go? Anything-
你有沒有什麼…有沒有什麼想去的地方？
You know what I'd really like to do, actually, is go to a craft store.
你知道我很想去哪麼，想去工藝品店
You're sweet.
你真好
Get some yarn and some beads?
買些針線和珠子？
I love your hair like that.
我喜歡你的頭髮
Thanks. It's a little darker.
謝謝，有點暗
Little bit.
有點
That's neat.
不錯啊
- Come on. - All right, Joey.
- 來吧 - 好吧，喬伊
Come on, Joey. Put it right in the glove.
來吧，喬伊，投進手套
- Strike. - Stee-rike!
- 好球
- Yeah. - Daddy!
- 不錯 - 爸爸
- Very nice. - Dad. Dad, throw it here.
- 很好 - 爸，爸，扔過來
- All right. Pop-up. - I got it.
- 好吧，拋高 - 我來
Can you see? Look there, little guy.
能看到麼？看那，小傢伙
Oops! Hey.
噢！嘿！
Ready? Here I go.
好了麼？我來了
- Want some chicken? - I'm full, honey.
- 還要雞肉麼？ - 我吃飽了，寶貝
- Are you sure? - Enough with the meat.
- 真的？ - 肉吃夠了
- No, no. Bring it on. - So how's business, Bill?
- 不，不，接著吃 - 工作怎麼樣，比爾？
Uh, well, you know, it'll pick up.
哦，你知道，會好的
Well, my offer stilI stands. You know that.
我的邀請仍然有效
I know. Thank you. Appreciate it.
我知道，謝謝，很感激
Why don't you let Jack help you out, Bill? It'd be an investment for us.
為什麼不讓傑克幫你，比爾，是筆好投資
Look, we're so good. Thank you.
我們可以的，謝謝
- Have you thought about my offer? - What's that?
- 考慮過我的邀請麼？ - 什麼邀請？
Beth wants to start taking Joey to church with them.
貝絲想帶喬伊跟他們一起去教堂
Really?
真的？
Don't you think it's important that he's raised with good values?
你不覺得教他好的價值觀很重要嗎？
- Sweetheart? - Excuse me. Need anything?
- 寶貝？ - 打斷下，還要什麼嗎？
I got some rib eye coming next. I'll be right back.
還有些肉眼排，我馬上回來
Okay, thanks. Sounds good.
好吧，謝謝，聽上去不錯
I know. I know.
我知道，我知道
Hey, buddy.
嘿，夥計
Hey, buddy, come here. Come on.
嘿，夥計，過來，過來
Come here. Hey, look at you! Hey, Camper.
來這兒，哦，瞧瞧你！嘿，坎波
- How you doing? - Your daddy's home!
- 你好麼？ - 爸爸回家了
Your daddy's home, Camper.
爸爸回家了，坎波
- Honey! - Phew.
- 寶貝！ - 喔呼
- Are you okay? - Yep.
- 你還好吧？ - 還好
- He bit you in the face. - No, it's-
- 他咬你的臉了？ - 不，只是…
- Camper, you bad dog! - He's just doin' his job.
- 坎波，你這壞狗 - 這是他的職責
I知 so sorry. Let's get you cleaned up.
我很抱歉，我幫你清理一下
I can't believe that.
我不敢相信
What a way to come home, huh?
就這麼回家，嗯？
You know, we're gonna have two salaries coming in.
知道麼，我們會有兩筆工資收入
We could fix things up a bit here.
我們可以把這埵n好弄一下
- That would be great. - Yeah.
- 那就太棒了 - 是的
You know, baby, I was thinking that once I get settled in...
寶貝，我有時在想，等我安頓下來…
We save a bit of money...
我們存點錢…
Um, we could start trying again.
我們可以從頭再來
You know?
知道麼
What do you think?
你覺得怎麼樣？
Do you want to start a family?
你想建立個家庭麼
Let's start a family.
我們建立個家
- Really? - Yeah.
- 真的？ - 是的
It壇 be that new life we talked about.
就是我們以前說過的新的生活
He could be the new me.
他可以做一個新的我
You want a boy?
你想要兒子？
Yeah.
是啊
I think every man wants a son, right?
每個男人都想要個兒子，嗯？
Come on. Run, Joey. Run!
跑啊，喬伊，跑啊
It's cold.
好冷
I telI you, I should get your sister to come over more often.
跟你說，我該讓你的妹妹常來
Get some dishes done around here.
來洗洗盤子
That's funny.
很好笑
- I'm just sick of it. - What's the big deal? Just let him go to church.
- 我有點煩了 - 有什麼大不了的，就讓他去教堂吧
Him going or not going is not the issue. He's our son.
不是他去不去的問題，他是我們的兒子
- She has no right. - Sweetie. Hey.
- 她沒有權力這樣 - 甜心，嘿
She's just jealous.
她就是嫉妒
You got all the looks, the talent.
你有長相，有才華
You got me.
你還有我
- It's perfectly understandable. - Really?
- 太好理解了 - 真的？
I知 glad you think this is amusing, because I don't.
很高興你覺得這好笑，我可不覺得
R & B ] - Rip. What's up, man? How are you?
理普，怎麼樣，夥計，你好嗎？
Yo, Rip.
嗨，理普
Who's that?
看誰來了？
- This was a great night. - Yeah.
- 今晚太棒了 - 是啊
You look like an angel.
你像個天使
Rip, I need to talk to you about something.
理普，有些事我想跟你談談
Yeah?
哦？
What?
怎麼了？
What is it, baby?
怎麼了，寶貝？
Um-
嗯…
Whatever it is, it's okay. You can tell me, you know.
不管是什麼，你可以跟我說的，沒事，好嗎？
After you went away...
你走之後…
It was so hard for me, Rip.
我過得很艱難，理普
It was just so hard.
太艱難了
- I know. Honey, I'm sorry. - No.
- 我知道，寶貝，我很抱歉 - 聽我說
I couldn't even find a job at first, and then, um-
我一開始連工作都找不到，然後…
then I-I-
然後我…
I found out I was pregnant.
我發現我懷孕了
You what?
你怎麼了？
And I didn't want to have an abortion, because it was-
我不想去做流產，因為…
It was a part of you and me, Rip.
孩子是你我的結合，理普
But I just, uh-
但我…
I just kept thinking...
我一直在想…
About how hard my childhood was...
想我的童年有多痛苦…
With- with my father...
我的父親…
And how hard yours was...
你的童年也痛苦…
And with how things were between you and me at that time.
還有我們之間發生的事情…
I just thought it was better for-
我只覺得最好還是…
So, my mother, she signed for you.
所以，我媽媽，她幫我簽的字
I gave- I gave the baby up for adoption.
我把孩子給人領養了
I gave him away.
我把他送給別人了
Please say something, Rip.
說話啊，理普
You said "him. "
你說「他」？
You said "him. " It was a boy?
你說「他」，是個兒子？
I gave him away.
我把他送人了
I- I gave away our boy.
我把我們的兒子送人了
I知- I'm so sorry.
我…我很抱歉
This is okay.
沒關係
I couldn't have been a father, honey- not then, not the man I was then.
我做不了父親，寶貝，那時的我不行的
You don't have to say that, sweetheart.
你不要這麼說，寶貝
Honey, don't- don't cry.
寶貝，別…別哭
Baby, we gotta get him back.
寶貝，我們把他要回來
We can't.
不行的
- We gave him away. - No.
- 我們已經放棄他了 - 不
Baby, I didn't sign anything. I didn't sign anything.
寶貝，我沒有簽字啊，我沒有簽字啊
We need to get our son back.
我們要把我們的兒子要回來
Okay? I'm gonna make this right for you.
好麼？我要替你挽回來
Okay? Come here. Come here.
好嗎？過來，過來
- It's okay. - Oh.
- 沒事的 - 噢
It's okay. All right?
沒關係的，好嗎？
We'll get him back.
我們把他要回來
Gotta go! I gotta go! I gotta go!
要走了！我要走了！我要走了！
Careful, sweetie. You have the eggs.
當心雞蛋，寶貝
- Why'd you give me the eggs? - 'Cause it was the lightest one.
- 為什麼把雞蛋給我？ - 因為雞蛋最輕
- I gotta pee! - Okay. Remember to put the toilet seat down.
- 我要尿尿了 - 好，記得放下馬桶蓋子
Put it up first, and then put it down.
先掀起來，再放下
I know how to use the toilet, Mommy.
我知道怎麼用馬桶，媽咪
This is Alyson Bower of the Ohio Department of Child Services.
我是俄亥俄兒童服務部的阿里森·鮑爾
I'm calling for Mr. and Mrs. -
請找…
Your Honor I'd just like to point out..
法官大人，我只想指出…
That this child is in private school...
這個孩子在私立學校讀書
And he's very well-adjusted.
被調教得很好
Whereas, these people, the birth parents, have no parental experience.
而這兩個人，他的親生父母沒有撫養小孩的經驗
I appreciate it, Mrs. Bower, but that doesn't change the forgery.
我理解，鮑爾女士，可這仍然是代簽字
Have a seat.
請坐
- Thank you. - Mrs. Porter?
- 謝謝 - 波特太太？
Who signed these papers?
誰簽署的這些文件？
Well, I assumed my husband did.
這個，我想應該是我丈夫
- I can explain, Your Honor- - I wasn't talking to you.
- 我解釋一下，法官大人… - 我沒和你說話
Mrs. Porter.
波特太太
After Rip was put away...
理普被帶走後…
I decided to adopt out the baby.
我決定把孩子送人領養
And so I took the papers to the prison...
我拿著文件去了監獄…
But because Rip and I weren't on speaking terms...
但當時理普和我還無法通話…
I gave them to a guard to give to him...
我請一個警官把文件轉交給他…
And someone on the inside must have signed his name.
堶悸眯w有人簽了他的名字
Let's I find out who did sign those papers, he's going to the same prison you did.
告訴你們，如果讓我知道誰簽了這些文件，他跟你一樣要坐牢
Yes, sir.
是的，大人
You're going to tell me...
你來告訴我…
That you didn't know about the pregnancy or the adoption?
你不知道懷孕和領養的事情？
No, sir, not until a couple weeks ago.
是的，大人，二周前才知道
And now you want to be a father?
現在你想做爸爸？
Yes, sir.
是的，大人
Before I was incarcerated, I was a very different man-
入獄之前我和現在很不一樣…
certainly not fit to be a husband or a father.
絕對不適合做丈夫或者父親
And, uh, my alcoholism...
我的酒癮…
Is a progressive illness...
是種持續的疾病
And healing is lifelong.
治癒要一輩子
And I've spent the last seven years rehabilitating.
過去七年我一直在康復
And the one thing that I've held on to, sir...
大人，我唯一的支柱就是…
Is- is my hope.
我的希望
My hope for a family...
我希望有個家庭…
To repair the damage that I've done...
希望修復我的過錯…
And my desire to be a father.
我希望做個父親
She's been in court all day? What's going on?
她在法庭堳搕F一整天了，怎麼回事？
Just let me try to talk to her.
我來跟她談談
Allyson Bower. Jack Campbell returning your call.
阿里森·鮑爾，我是傑克·坎貝爾回你的電話
What kind of situation?
什麼情況？
Living room, uh, kitchen table.
客廳，哦，廚房的桌子
Got a few fish.
有幾隻魚
Um- And he's got his own room.
還有他的房間
I知 doing a bit of work on it.
這堶n重新裝修一下
Uh, we just got some toys today.
今天剛剛買了些玩具
- Yeah, we got him a train set. - Mm-hmm.
- 買了一套玩具火車 - 嗯
Have you given any thought to schools?
有沒有想過學校的事情？
Yes. The public school's just down the street here...
是的，這條街上就有一間公立學校…
And it's got a very good student-teacher ratio.
師生比例非常合理
I actually went there. It's a good school.
我自己曾在那上學，不錯的學校
- So you're a local girl. - Yeah.
- 你是本地人？ - 是的
All right. What about his diet?
好吧，他的飲食怎麼樣？
Yeah. Mom?
是啊，媽咪？
I致e actually planned out all of his meals already.
其實我已經把他的飲食都計劃好了
Um, lots of protein and veggies.
許多蛋白質和蔬菜
Um, no fried. No fried food.
沒油炸的，沒油炸的食物
We're cutting that out. No more fast food.
我們不吃這個了，也不吃快餐
- Right. - I've even made a schedule.
- 是的 - 我還做了個時間表
Um- Oh.
嗯
These are all child safety locks, by the way.
順便說一下，這些都是兒童保護裝置
Yep. Installed them myself.
是的，我自己裝的
Well, there's a lot more to raising a child than toys and locks.
好吧，撫養一個孩子不僅僅靠玩具和裝置
We know.
我們知道
Look, I can see that you've worked really hard...
聽著，我看得出你們已經很努力了…
But that doesn't change the fact that you are ripping this boy away...
但這改變不了一個事實，你是在把這個孩子從習慣的…
From the only life he's ever known.
生活環境剝離了出來
He's coming from another world.
他來自完全不同的世界
Do you have any idea what that's going to do to him?
你們可知道這對他會有什麼影響嗎？
Have you thought about it?
你們有考慮過這些嗎？
I don't understand why this is our problem. They made the mistake.
我不知道這怎麼成了我們的問題，是他們犯的錯誤
They should have notarized the signature.
他們應該去把簽名做公正
You're right. You wanna sue Ohio D.C.S.? We'll probably win.
你說得對，你要起訴俄亥俄兒童服務部？你也許會贏
I don't wanna sue, Tom. This isn't about money.
我不想起訴，湯姆，這不是錢的問題
But we got a problem. It's Ohio case law.
但我們有個問題，俄亥俄判例法
It's firm.
這是確定的
There were eight forged adoptions, all invalidated.
有八起虛假領養案，全部無效
And in every case, the child was returned to the biological parents.
每個案子，孩子都被交還給了親生父母
- This judge has no choice. - You gotta help me, Tom.
- 法官別無選擇 - 你一定要幫我，湯姆
Please. There's gotta be somethin'.
求你了，一定有辦法的
Look, Jack. Listen to me.
傑克，聽我說
We won a lot of battles together, you and me...
我們一起贏過很多官司，你我一起…
But we're not gonna win this one.
但這一次我們贏不了
So let me tell you what I would do if it were me.
我來告訴你，如果是我我會怎麼做
I would stop wasting my time talking to lawyers.
我不會把時間浪費在和律師談
Do you follow me?
你懂我意思麼？
The interior's good. Yeah.
內部還不錯
All right. We got her.
好了，這邊有我們
What do you think?
你覺得怎麼樣？
Wow.
哇哦
I've been thinking a lot about him.
關於他我考慮了很多
I just, uh-
我…嗯…
I'm scared. I want this to work out so bad, and-
我有點害怕，我非常希望一切順利…
- Honey. - Huh?
- 寶貝 - 嗯？
You're gonna be a great father.
你會是個優秀的父親
- Jack, how are you? - Thanks for coming. Please, sit down.
- 傑克，你好麼？ - 謝謝你能來，請坐
You're talking about reversing the ruling of an Ohio judge. I have no legal authority.
你說的是否決一個俄亥俄法官的決定，我沒有這個權力
Curtis, you're a congressman.
柯蒂斯，你是議員
Call in some favors for me. Twist some arms. I know how it works.
幫我求求情，找找關係，我知道有用的
It's the state judiciary, and I can't interfere with that.
這是州司法系統，我不能干預的
What if it was your son?
如果是你兒子你會怎樣？
What if it was Max? Think about that.
如果是麥克斯？你想想看
Come on, Jack. That's not fair.
得了，傑克，不能這樣想
There's a woman coming down here in three days to take Joey.
一個女人三天後就會來帶走喬伊
- Do you understand that? - Hey, hey, hey. Calm down.
- 你明白麼？ - 嘿，嘿，嘿，冷靜
Look, I realize it's an election year, okay?
聽著，我知道今年是選舉年
- And these aren't popular cases to be associated with. - What are you talking about?
- 你不想和這種案子扯上關係 - 你在說什麼啊？
This has nothing to do with my political career. Are you kidding me?
這和我的政治生涯有什麼關係，你開玩笑吧？
I知 asking you to put yourself on the line for once...
我求你就冒這一次險…
To save my son.
幫幫我兒子
Look.
聽著
I know you're under a lot of pressure. I know that.
我知道你壓力很大，我理解
But I'm sorry. I can't.
但我很抱歉，不行
I壇 like to help you, Jack, but, um...
我很想幫你，傑克，可…
It's a state matter.
這是州級事務
My hands are tied.
我無權干預
I知 sorry.
我很抱歉
Send him to your parents.
送他去你父母那兒
That's the first place they'll look, honey.
他們第一個找的地方就是那堙A寶貝
Well, if he's not here when they get here, what-
如果他們來這，他不在的話…
Then they'll send us to jail.
我們是要坐牢的
What good are we then?
這有什麼好處？
We have to send him on the first visit.
我們必須送他去見第一次
Just until I can figure something out.
我會想出辦法的
Let me see these feet.
讓我看看你的腳
- Ow! - Oh!
- 噢！ - 喔！
Hey, you count one, two, three, all right?
嘿，你數一二三，好嗎？
- One- - Two.
- 一… - 二
Three.
三
Ouch, Mama.
噢，媽媽
That was a good one.
這個不錯
It was all-
這都…
Hey, Joey. Hey, Joe.
嘿，喬伊
I want to telI you something.
我要告訴你些事情
You're gonna go on a little trip...
你要進行一次旅行…
To a place called Ohio.
去一個叫俄亥俄的地方
All right?
好嗎？
Where's Ohio?
俄亥俄在哪？
It's pretty far, so you're gonna have to take a plane.
很遠，所以你要坐飛機
But remember, you love planes, right?
但記住，你喜歡飛機，對吧
Why do I have to go?
我為什麼非要去？
Well...
這…
There's this woman, and she's really nice.
有一位女士，她人很好
You don't remember her, but she knew you when you were a little baby.
你不記得她了，但你很小的時候她就認識你了
And she asked if you could come for a visit...
她邀請你去拜訪…
And Daddy and I said yes.
爸爸和我答應了
Hey, Joey.
嘿，喬伊
Everything's gonna be fine, all right?
一切都會沒事的，好嗎？
You got nothing to be afraid of.
沒什麼好擔心的
Look at me, buddy. Hey.
看著我，夥計，嘿
I want you to come with me.
我要你跟我一起
I can't.
我受不了了
Aah!
啊！
I wanna stay here with you.
我要留在這堜M你一起
You listen to me.
聽我說
Your mother and I will always be with you...
你媽媽和我會一直在你身邊…
No matter where you go.
不管你去哪
You understand that?
你懂麼？
Hmm?
嗯？
Okay.
好吧
I love you.
我愛你
Ms. Bower.
鮑爾女士
Good morning.
早上好
Mr. and Mrs. Campbell, I'm very sorry.
坎貝爾夫婦，我很抱歉
I know this must be difficult.
我知道這很讓人難受
"Difficult"?
「難受」？
Do they teach you to say that, Ms. Bower?
他們教你這麼說的麼，鮑爾女士？
There are a couple of things I need to go over with you.
還有兩件事情要你們處理一下
This has the itinerary and all of my information in it.
這堶惘釵瘚{和我的所有信息
Now, on the first visit...
第一次見面…
We're gonna tell Joey that the Porters are just friends.
我們告訴喬伊，波特夫婦只是朋友
The next time, we'll refer to them as "the other Mommy and Daddy. "
下次，我會說他們是另一個「爸爸和媽媽」
And on the final visit, he'll be told the truth.
最後一次，再告訴他真相
Do you have children, Mrs. Bower?
你有孩子嗎，鮑爾女士？
Yes. Yes, I do.
是的，我有
And I am very sorry.
我很抱歉
All right, all right. What if something happens?
好吧，好吧，如果出什麼事怎麼辦？
- I'm sorry? - Ms. Bower.
- 你說什麼？ - 鮑爾女士
I know why Rip Porter went to prison.
我知道理普·波特為什麼入獄
Mr. Porter's had years of rehabilitation-
波特先生多年來一直在康復
and anger management.
學習控制憤怒
Come on.
得了吧
And the court has deemed him a fit parent.
法庭認定他是合適的父親
Now, I've personally been to their home.
我本人去過他們家
- It's a suitable environment. - A suitable environment?
- 那是個合適的環境 - 合適的環境？
Joey's not going anywhere. You can leave now, Ms. Bower.
喬伊哪也不去，你可以走了，鮑爾女士
Good-bye.
再見
Mr. Campbell, I understand your frustration...
坎貝爾先生，我知道你很沮喪…
But it's either me...
如果不是我來…
Or two uniformed police officers.
就是兩個穿制服的警官
I致e done it both ways.
兩種我都參與過
Believe me, this way is best for Joey.
相信我，這樣對喬伊最好不過了
Ms. Bower...
鮑爾女士…
If anything happens to my son while I'm clearing this mess up...
我在解決這問題期間，如果我的兒子出什麼事…
I知 gonna hold you personally responsible.
你個人要負全責
Jack. Jack.
傑克，傑克
Come here, baby.
過來，寶貝
Good morning. You must be Joey. I'm Allyson.
早上好，你一定是喬伊，我是阿里森
Hey, sweetie?
嘿，寶貝
- Listen to Mom, okay? - No.
- 聽媽媽說，好嗎？ - 不
- This is the woman that's gonna take you to Ohio. - No!
- 這位女士將帶你去俄亥俄 - 不！
- It's okay, sweetie. - No!
- 沒事的，寶貝
Baby, it's gonna be okay. Mommy and Daddy love you so much.
寶貝，沒事的，爸爸和媽咪都很愛你
- I don't wanna go! - It's gonna be okay. We'll be right here when you get back.
- 我不想去 - 沒事的，你回來時我們還在這
- Will you give me a moment with my family? - Of course.
- 讓我們一家人待一會？ - 當然
Come here, sweetie.
過來，寶貝
We have to put your jacket on.
我們得給你穿上夾克
Listen.
聽著
I want you to be a big boy, okay?
你要做個大孩子，好麼
Okay, you be brave. I know you can.
好嗎，你要勇敢，我知道你可以的
I wanna stay with you.
我要和你在一起
Will you come with me to the airplane?
你和我一起坐飛機嗎？
We can't go with you to the airplane.
我們不能和你一起坐飛機
- I'm gonna take you to the car, okay? - No.
- 我送你上車，好麼？ - 不
- I'm sorry. - Please, I don't want to go.
- 我對不起你 - 求你了，我不想去
Please don't take me. I don't wanna go!
別讓我走，我不想去
No, I don't wanna go!
不，我不想走！
Rip, they're here.
理普，他們來了
They're here.
他們來了
- He's got your eyes. - Yeah?
- 他的眼睛像你 - 是嗎？
- Ain't that somethin'? - Hello.
- 太神奇了 - 你們好
Let me get the gate for ya.
我來給你們開門
Ready?
可以了麼？
Mr. and Mrs. Porter, this is Joey.
波特先生和太太，這是喬伊
Hi there.
你好
What a big, handsome boy you are.
你可真是個帥氣的大男孩
Welcome to our home.
歡迎來我們家
Can I give you a hug?
我能抱你一下嗎？
This is my wife, Wendy...
這是我太太，溫蒂
And, uh...
並且…
My name's Richard.
我叫理查德
Some people call me Rip. You can call me whatever you want.
有人叫我理普，你隨便怎麼稱呼我都可以
- Nice to meet you. - Joey?
- 見到你很高興 - 喬伊？
Rip and Wendy are your new friends.
理普和溫蒂是你的新朋友
Now, you need to listen to them and obey them...
現在，你要聽他們的話
Just as you would your parents.
就像聽你父母的話一樣
You understand?
你懂麼？
Is that your suitcase? Can I get it for you?
這是你的箱子？我能幫你拿嗎？
Oh, wow! You got an elephant in there?
噢，哇哦，有只大象在堶掠
You wanna see your room? I fixed it up myself for you.
想看看你房間嗎？我幫你裝修的
Oh, hey, we got a dog in the back named Camper.
嘿，我們後院有隻狗叫坎波
- I got a dog named Gus. - In the backyard there.
- 我有隻狗叫嘎斯 - 在後院呢
Yeah? Well, come on in.
是嗎？進來吧
I need you to sign right there.
我需要你在這媄惘r
Thank you for everything.
謝謝你做的一切
Just remember that he's six and in a new world.
記住他才六歲，一切都很陌生
I値l check in tomorrow.
我明早再來看看
I want their address, Tom. I want to know where he works.
我要他們的地址，湯姆，我要知道他在哪工作
Give me his rap sheet, anything else you can get your hands on.
他的判決書，所有你能拿到的資料
I need this done, and I need it now.
我需要這些，馬上就需要
- You understand? - You need to be careful Court orders-
- 你懂嗎？ - 你要小心法庭的命令…
I've been careful, Tom, and Joey's gone.
我一直很小心，湯姆，可喬伊走了
- Now, please. - Okay I'll take care of it
- 馬上，拜託 - 好吧，我來搞定
I'm gonna go to Ohio and see what this guy wants.
我要去俄亥俄看看這傢伙要幹嘛
- Whoa! This is so cool! - Yeah?
- 哇哦，這太酷了？ - 是嗎？
Wait. Check this out.
等等，看這個
For bringing up lunch.
送午飯上來的
- Ready? - Yep.
- 好了嗎？ - 好了
All right. Okay, you're gonna put it in up here.
好吧，你把它放在這兒
Watch my fingers.
注意我的手指
Give her a good smack. There you go.
使勁來一下，幹得不錯
- One, two, three. - Camper. Go get it!
一，二，三
- Cookies! - Hey!
- 曲奇？ - 嘿！
Actually, sorry.
抱歉啦
No girls allowed.
女孩不許進
Aw. I guess I'm gonna have to take them back then.
噢，那我把餅乾拿回去了
You have some cookies, so you can come up.
你有曲奇就可以上來
- I guess you can come up if you have cookies. - Okay.
- 有餅乾就可以上來 - 好吧
So, little Joe, what do you like to do?
小喬，你一般喜歡做什麼？
I mostly like to sail.
我很喜歡出海
I know how to steer a boat myself.
我自己知道怎麼掌船舵
Do your mom and dad have a boat?
你的爸媽有條船？
Yeah, a big sailboat. But it also has a motor.
是的，大帆船，不過也有馬達
- Mmm. - You know what we could do?
- 嗯 - 你知道我們可以做什麼嗎？
We could go up to Dillon Lake tomorrow.
我們明天可以去迪倫湖
They got these little boats that you can rent. You can steer it.
那有小船可以租，你可以掌舵
- How 'bout that? - Yeah, that could be fun.
- 怎麼樣？ - 好啊，一定很好玩
I知 done with my cookies now.
我不想吃曲奇了
So, ready to take a shower, little man?
要去沖個澡嗎，小大人
I don't like showers.
我不喜歡淋浴
Listen, you gotta get cleaned up before bed, right?
聽著，你上床前要先洗乾淨，好嗎？
Can't go to bed dirty.
髒了不能上床
I don't wanna shower.
我不想沖澡
I just wanna go home.
我想回家
Can I please go home?
請問我能回家嗎？
Babe, you know what?
寶貝，你知道麼
What you could do is go to the bathroom with Wendy...
你可以跟溫蒂一起去廁所…
And just wash up your face and hands...
洗洗你的臉和手…
And, you know, maybe that'll make you feel better.
也許你會感覺好一些
- Yeah. - Okay? All right?
- 好吧 - 好嗎？
That's a great idea.
這個主意不錯
But, um, next time...
不過，下次…
You gotta take a shower, okay?
你得沖澡，好嗎
Okay.
好的
- Hey, let's test the rope swing. - Yeah!
- 嘿，我們試試鞦韆吧 - 好啊！
- All right. - Oh, boy.
- 好吧 - 哦，天啊
- Ready? - Have fun.
- 好了嗎 - 好好玩
All right.
好了
- Whoo! - That's pretty cool.
- 喔噢！ - 太酷了
Help!
救命啊！
- All right. Your turn. - Okay.
- 好了，到你了 - 好
What a cute nose you have.
你的鼻子真可愛
Is it kind of upturned?
有點向上翹的
Kind of like mine.
有點像我的
Hmm.
嗯
It's grape juice.
這是葡萄汁
Non-fermented.
新鮮的
A toast...
乾杯…
To my perfect wife...
敬我完美的老婆…
And my perfect son.
和我完美的兒子
You know...
知道嗎…
I致e been thinkin' a lot about the day that he was born...
他出生那天的事我想了很久
And how I felt when they took him away from me...
他們把他抱走的時候我什麼感覺
Out of my arms...
從我懷堜磛哄K
And how I was never gonna...
我從那以後再也沒…
See his little head again...
看過他的小腦袋…
Or smell his skin.
聞他的皮膚
It's okay.
沒事了
Nobody-
沒人…
Nobody's gonna take him away from us again, okay?
沒人再能把他奪走，好嗎？
I know.
我知道
It's okay.
沒事的
It's just, um...
只是…
His mother must be feeling the same way I did, maybe worse.
他的媽媽一定和我當時的感受一樣，也許更糟
Yeah.
是的
But, babe, somebody's gonna lose.
可是寶貝，失去在所難免
It's not gonna be us this time.
這次不會是我們
You are his mother...
你，是他的母親…
And we are his parents...
我們是他的親生父母…
And it's right for him to be with us.
他跟我們在一起是應該的
Okay?
好嗎？
- Okay. - Just remember.
- 好 - 要記住
Appreciate dinner thank you.
謝謝你的晚餐
Yeah, of course.
沒事
So, did Beth mention that we're going away in a few weeks to Haiti?
貝絲有沒有說過我們要去海地幾周？
- Mm-mmm. - Yeah.
- 嗯 - 是的
What's in Haiti?
為什麼去海地？
- We're gonna take the kids on their first mission trip. - Oh, yeah?
- 我們要帶孩子去第一次教會旅行 - 是麼？
Yeah, we got our new church to sponsor an orphanage...
是的，我們的教堂資助了一家孤兒院…
That we've been working with in Port-au-Prince...
我們一直有合作，在太子港
And this year we're gonna help 'em renovate the compound.
今年我們要幫他們整修
We were thinking that if you guys wanna come...
我們在想如果你們想來的話…
It might be a good time to get away.
離開一下也許會好一點
Or Bill can take the kids, and I can stay here with you.
或者比爾帶孩子去，我留下來陪你
- You know, it's really whatever you want. - Stop!
- 隨你們的心願 - 住手！
- What, guys? - Mom, he's writing on my homework.
- 怎麼了，孩子們？ - 媽，他在我作業上寫字
- I did not. - Yeah, you did.
- 我沒有 - 你寫了
- Not tonight. - Yeah, you know what? I think it's time for bed.
- 今晚別鬧 - 知道嗎，我覺得你們該上床了
Right now, please.
馬上，請上床去
- Good night, Uncle Jack. - Good night.
- 晚安，傑克叔叔 - 晚安
Good night, Mom. Good night, Dad.
晚安，媽媽 晚安，爸爸
It's really good for them to see what other parts of the world can be like.
看看世界其他的地方對他們很有好處
Maybe you should take them to Ohio.
也許你該帶他們去俄亥俄
When does he come back?
他什麼時候回來？
He comes back tomorrow afternoon.
他明天下午回來
And then he goes again in two weeks...
然後兩周後要再去
And the next time he doesn't come back at all.
再下次，他就不回來了
Hey!
嘿
- Hi, buddy! - What's goin' on, J.?
- 嗨，夥計 - 怎麼樣，小喬？
- Oh! Mmm! I missed you. - Hi, Dad.
- 噢媽媽，我想你 - 嗨，爸爸
- Mmm! - Look what Wendy gave me.
- 嗯！ - 看看溫蒂給我什麼了
He says it went all right.
他說一切還不錯
And we went to a lake, and I steered a paddleboat all by myself.
我們去了一個湖，我自己開著一條船
And I didn't want to take a shower...
我不想沖澡
But Wendy said if I did next time...
溫蒂說，下次如果我沖澡…
She'd get me my own DVD for my room.
她會在我屋堜韙@台DVD
- Was Wendy nice to you? - Yeah.
- 溫蒂對你好嗎？ - 是的
Wendy was really nice. She cooks good too.
溫蒂很好，做飯也很好吃
- How was Rip? - Good. He's really funny.
- 理普怎麼樣？ - 很好，他很好玩
We're building a tree house...
我們在蓋一個小樹屋…
And we cut part of Wendy's pillowcase out...
我們把溫蒂的枕頭套剪了一塊…
And then we spray-painted a skull and crossbone.
塗上了骷髏和十字架…
And we have a bucket that, like, she can put something in...
我們還有個小籃子，她可以把東西放堶情K
And then we pull it up with the rope.
我們用繩子把它拉上去
It's so cool.
太酷了
They're bribing him.
他們在討好他
I never thought he'd actually want to go back.
沒想到他真的還會想回去
- What if he wants to be with them? - He's six years old.
- 如果他想和他們在一起怎麼辦？ - 他才六歲
What if he has some deep connection to these people?
如果他跟他們有某種很深的情感怎麼辦？
- Like, he feels that- - He doesn't even know them.
- 好像，他能感覺到… - 他根本不認識他們
He came from them, Jack.
他是他們的血肉，傑克
Mom, I'm done with my bath.
媽媽，我泡完澡了
All right. I'm gonna go to Ohio first thing in the morning.
好吧，我明天一早就去俄亥俄
- Yo, Rip. - Yo!
- 嗨，理普 - 嗨
- See you Sunday.
- 週日見
Peace out, man.
當心點，夥計
- Take it easy. - See you later.
- 放心 - 再見
See you later.
再見
Mr. Porter.
波特先生
Yeah.
是的
I知 Jack Campbell, Joey's father.
我是傑克·坎貝爾，喬伊的父親
It's good to meet you, Jack.
見到你很高興，傑克
How much do you want, Rip?
你要多少錢，理普？
Come again?
再說一遍？
This is an amendment to the original adoption.
這是原始領養文件的修正條款
You sign this, I give you half a million dollars in cash.
把這文件簽了，我給你五十萬現金
- That's a whole lot of money, Jack. - Yes, sir.
- 這可是大筆錢啊，傑克 - 沒錯，先生
You sign it, I pay you, and we walk away.
你簽字，我付錢，我們各走各路
What do you say?
你說怎麼樣？
You come up with $500,000 in cash, Jack...
你帶著五十萬現金，傑克
I知 betting you could come up with a million.
我打賭你可以拿出一百萬
Okay. Make it a million.
好吧，就一百萬
That was fast. That was fast, Jack.
很乾脆，傑克，很乾脆
- Let's make it a million. - Yeah?
- 就一百萬 - 是嗎？
Boy, you said that so fast...
天，你可說的真乾脆…
I figure you can come up with two.
我猜你還能出二百萬
Fine. Just sign it.
可以，只要你簽字
Two million dollars.
二百萬美元
Then I'd be just like you, Jack.
我就和你一樣了，傑克
Big house...
大房子…
Big boat and big shot, huh?
大遊艇，了不起，嗯？
Yeah, that's right. You can be anything you want, Rip.
是的，沒錯，你想要做什麼都行，理普
Anything at all.
怎麼樣都可以
What do you want, Rip? What do you want?
你想要什麼，理普？你想要什麼？
I want my son, okay?
我要我的兒子，行嗎？
And you can't have him, not for no money.
你不能得到他，有錢也不行
Not two million, not 10 million, 'cause my son ain't for sale.
二百萬，一千萬，都不行，因為我的兒子不賣
Whoa, whoa, hold on. Rip, listen to me one second.
等等，等等，理普，聽我說
Just listen to me. Please. Please.
聽我說，拜託，拜託
With that kind of money, you could start over.
有了這筆錢，你可以從頭開始
You could have as many kids as you want. You understand?
你想要生多少孩子都可以，你懂嗎？
What am I, a dog? You don't know me.
你以為我是什麼，狗嗎？你不瞭解我
What, you can't have any kids?
你不瞭解我。怎麼？你生不了孩子？
You got no bullets in your gun, big shot, huh?
你槍堥S子彈，嗯？大人物
You don't know me!
你不瞭解我！你不瞭解我！
- You- - I'll send you back to prison, you hear me?
- 你… - 我要送你回監獄，你聽到了嗎？
You're going to prison! You're the one violating the court order!
進監獄的是你！你違法了法庭的命令！
Either way, you can't have my son.
不管怎麼樣，你別想得到我兒子
What happened?
怎麼了？
He doesn't want the money.
他不想要錢
He wants Joey.
他要喬伊
Jack, he can't do this. He assaulted you.
傑克，他不能這樣，他打你了
We call the police. We file a report.
我們報告警察，寫份報告
Molly.
莫莉
It won't work.
沒用的
Why not?
為什麼？
Because if I report him...
如果我報告了…
I go to jaiI too.
我也要進監獄
Okay.
好吧
What do we do?
我們怎麼辦？
I don't know.
不知道
You don't know?
你不知道？
That's it?
就這樣了？
You try to buy him off, it doesn't work, and now you're done?
你要收買他，沒成功，就完了？
What else do you want me to do?
你還要我怎麼樣？
You tell me. What else should I do, Molly?
你告訴我，我們還能怎樣，莫莉？
I don't know- something, anything.
我不知道，隨便，隨便什麼
You're his father. You don't just give up.
你是他父親，你不能這樣放棄
I知 not giving up! I've done everything!
我沒放棄，我已竭盡所能了
I don't care what it takes.
無論什麼代價
I知 not giving up my son.
我不會放棄我兒子
You know what? You're something, you know?
知道嗎？你真了不起
- I'm not giving up my son! - Look at my face!
- 我不會放棄我兒子！ - 看著我的臉！
Look at me!
看著我！
What a horrible father I am.
我是個糟糕的父親！
I致e done everything, Molly.
什麼辦法我都想了，莫莉
Why don't you do something?
你怎麼不做點什麼？
Do something.
隨便什麼
I知 going to bed.
我要睡覺了
Please! Don't take my baby.
求你不要搶走我的寶貝！
- Oh, baby. - I know.
- 噢，寶貝 - 我知道
- I'm sorry. - You don't need this, darling.
- 我很抱歉 - 你不需要這個，親愛的
Baby, don't. I do. I just need it.
寶貝，別倒，我需要，我需要這個
- I know. This is not gonna fix things. - No, no, no, no!
- 我知道，這解決不了問題 - 不，不，不，不！
Don't, don't, don't! No, no, no!
不要，不要，不要！
Hey! Don't!
嘿，不要倒！
Honey, you don't need that. You don't need that anymore.
寶貝，你不需要酒了，你再也不需要了
Please, baby? You don't need to.
求你了，寶貝，你不要這樣
Please, no.
求你了，別
- Get- Get out. - No, no. Baby, no. No, please.
- 出…出去 - 不要，寶貝，不要，求你了
I love you so much.
我好愛你
Please tell me you've changed, baby. Please.
告訴我你改了，寶貝，求你了
I- I lost seven years.
我…我失去了七年時間
You gonna be okay, buddy?
你會沒事的，夥計？
Yeah. We're gonna paint my tree house.
是的，我們要給樹屋上油漆
- Joey, you ready to go? - Yeah.
- 喬伊，可以走了嗎？ - 好了
Bye, Dad.
再見，爸爸
I love you.
我愛你
I love you too.
我也愛你
- Put your seat belt on, bud. - Okay.
- 繫上安全帶，夥計 - 好的
Bye, sweetie.
再見，甜心
- Paw. - Nice.
- 爪子 - 好的
One, two, three!
一，二，三！
You stacked his deck.
你堆在他那堆了
Hey, just one thing, so I can remember.
嘿，有個事情，別忘了
Let's you had a birthday coming up...
你的生日要到了…
What would you want to eat on your birthday?
過生日你想吃什麼？
A- A chicken cake.
雞肉蛋糕
Chicken cake? Chicken-flavored cake?
雞肉蛋糕？雞肉味道的蛋糕？
- Chicken with cake. - Chicken with cake?
- 雞肉和蛋糕 - 雞肉和蛋糕？
- A chicken cake. - You want a cake made in the shape of a chicken?
- 雞肉蛋糕 - 你要一個雞形狀的蛋糕？
- No. - You want chicken inside the cake?
- 不是 - 雞肉放在蛋糕堙H
- Chicken inside the cake. - All right, I'm gonna file that away.
- 雞肉放在蛋糕 - 好吧，我記住了
All right, let's go.
好吧，我們開始
One, two, three.
一，二，三
- Joker! I win. - I win!
- 大王！我贏了 - 我贏了
You won? I thought joker was better than everything.
你贏了？我以為大王最大啊
No. That was before.
不，那是以前
- Before what? - When I had joker.
- 什麼以前？ - 我有大王的時候
Reminds me of someone.
讓我想起一個人
All right, card shark, ready to hop in the shower?
好吧，高手，準備去沖澡嗎？
I don't want to take a shower.
我不想沖澡
Oh, we gotta get you clean somehow.
噢，我們要把你弄乾淨
Look at you. P. U.
看你，髒孩子
P. U. to you.
你才是髒孩子
Now, listen, we gotta get you in there and get you cleaned up.
現在聽著，我們把你帶進去弄乾淨
Remember we talked? We got different rules here.
我們談過的，記得麼？我們這堣ㄓ@樣
I need you to go and jump in the shower. Okay?
我要你去沖個淋浴，好嗎？
You can do it.
你可以的
You know what? Why don't I take care of it?
不如，我來吧
Honey, don't spoil him.
寶貝，別慣著他
- I'm not spoiling him. It's just that- - It's fine.
- 我沒慣著他，只是… - 沒事的
- It's just that I think that- - He's a big boy.
- 只是我覺得… - 他是個大孩子了
You're a big boy. Come on. Get your gear. Let's go.
你是大孩子了，來吧，拿上你的東西，我們走
Come on, bud.
來吧，夥計
Hop in the shower.
來洗個淋浴
I don't wanna take a shower.
我不想洗淋浴
Doesn't work like that here, buddy. Come on.
在這媟Q不通，夥計，過來
I need you to obey me...
我要你服從我…
And I need you to get in the bathroom.
我要你去廁所
You know, I think that you're really upsetting him now.
知道麼，我覺得你現在真的讓他不高興了
No, you know what? I'm-I'm- I'm actually the one who's getting upset.
不，你知道嗎，現在是我不高興了
- So would you just- - Okay.
- 你能不能就… - 好吧
Come here. Come here, sweetie.
過來，寶貝，過來
Here, we'll go together, okay?
過來，我們一起去，好嗎
It'll be fun, all right? Come on.
會很好玩的，好嗎？過來
Let's go, Joey.
走吧，喬伊
Please, sweetheart. It's only water.
來吧，寶貝，只是水而已
It's nothin'.
沒關係的
Come on. What are you doing?
得了，你們在幹嘛
Come on, buddy, in the shower.
過來，寶貝，去淋浴
- Come on. - I don't wanna take a shower.
- 來吧 - 我不想沖淋浴
- He's really scared of it. He's really scared. - It'll be fun.
- 他真的很害怕啊，很害怕 - 會很好玩的
- I don't think we should push him. - He's a big boy, baby.
- 我覺得我們不該逼他 - 他是個大孩子了，寶貝
He's not made of sugar. He's not gonna melt.
他不是糖做的，不會化的
- I don't wanna take a shower. - Just take your shirt off, and let's get going.
- 我不想洗淋浴 - 把衣服脫了，我們去洗
- No. - You wanna do it together?
- 不 - 你想一起洗嗎？
We'll do it with our clothes on. Come on. It'll be fun. Whoo!
我們穿著衣服跟你一起洗，很好玩的，來吧
Come on. You ready? Whoo-hoo!
來吧，準備好了嗎？喔呼……
Rip, what are you doing? Rip, stop it!
理普，你在幹嘛，理普，你住手！
Stop that!
停下來
- Rip, this is not fun! You're scaring him! - Right?
- 理普，這不好玩，你嚇著他了！ - 是嗎？
- It's okay. We're having fun. - It's not okay!
- 沒事的，我們在玩 - 這樣不行
It's not fun. You're scaring him.
這不好玩，你嚇著他了
- He's okay, baby. He's okay. He's fine. - He's not!
- 他沒事的，寶貝，他沒事，他很好 - 他不好
- Rip, you're hurting him! Rip, you're hurting him! - Ow!
理普，你弄痛他了，你弄痛他了
- Stop! You're hurting him! - Okay.
- 住手！你弄痛他了 - 好吧
- This is hurting him. Stop it. - You okay?
- 你弄痛他了，住手！ - 你沒事吧？
- You're okay. - No!
- 你沒事！ - 不！
You hurt him.
你弄痛他了
Listen, listen.
聽著，聽著
I need to telI you something, okay?
我要告訴你件事，好嗎？
Wendy- Wendy is your real mommy.
溫蒂…溫蒂才是你的媽媽
- Rip, not now. - Shh, baby.
- 理普，現在別說 - 噓，寶貝
This is not the right time.
現在說這不合適
- And I'm your real daddy, okay? - No, you're not.
- 我才是你真正的爸爸，好嗎？ - 不，你不是的
And you came here to live with us.
你要來和我們住在一起
- No, you're not! - Yes, I am.
- 不，你不是的！ - 是的，我是
- I'm your real daddy, and this is your real mommy. - Rip.
- 我是你的親爸爸，她是你的親媽媽 - 理普
- I wanna see my daddy! - I am your daddy.
- 我要找我爸爸 - 我就是你爸爸
- I wanna go home! - You are home. You are home.
- 我要回家！ - 這是你家！這是你家！
I wanna go home!
我要回家！
- It's okay. It's okay. - Rip.
- 沒事，沒事 - 理普
It's okay.
沒事的
- That's enough. That's enough. - It's okay.
- 夠了，夠了 - 沒關係的
Come here, sweetie.
過來，甜心
That's enough for one night. That's enough.
今晚夠了，夠了
Why?
因為你還沒準備好，你需要更多的時間
Where you goin'?
我去洗臉，然後去睡覺
Get the camera. I want a shot of that bruise right now.
拿相機來，我要把這個傷拍下來
- Who are you calling? - Allyson Bower.
- 你跟誰打電話？ - 阿里森·鮑爾
Call Dr. Riley and tell him that I'll be in there in 15 minutes with Joey.
打電話給萊利醫生，告訴他我帶著喬伊十五分鐘以後到
All of this is gonna accomplish what? What- you're gonna file a lawsuit, send Porter to jail?
做這一切又能怎樣？你要打官司，送波特進監獄？
- I'm gonna send him to prison. - You said it yourself. That's not gonna do us any good.
- 我要送他進監獄 - 你自己說的，那對我們沒好處
We could put Porter away for the rest of his life. Joey still won't be ours.
我可以讓波特從此消失，但喬伊始終不是我們的孩子
- This is Jack Campbell for Allyson Bower. - Jack.
- 我是傑克·坎貝爾找阿里森·鮑爾 - 傑克
What then? What?
然後呢？然後怎麼辦？
We have to leave.
我們必須離開
We have to pack our things and go.
我們必須收拾行李離開
Look.
你瞧
We've both been thinking it. We just haven't wanted to say it.
我們都考慮很久了，我本不想說的
We can't win, Jack.
我們贏不了的，傑克
You want to run away?
你想逃走 ？
Listen to me.
聽我說
No one is coming to save us.
沒人會來救我們
Go where?
去哪？
Out of the country. Anywhere.
離開這個國家，隨便去哪
You realize what you're saying, don't you?
你知道你在說什麼嗎，你知道嗎？
I do.
我知道
All of this would be gone.
這些都會沒有了
We'd never be able to come back.
我們再也不能回來了
All our friends...
我們的朋友…
Your sister-
你妹妹…
We'd never be able to contact them again.
我們再也不能聯絡他們
We'd have Joey.
我們有喬伊
Yeah.
是的
- Hey. Everything okay? - Yeah, yeah. Of course.
- 嘿，沒事吧？ - 是的，是的，當然
- How are you? - Good. You want some tea?
- 你還好嗎？ - 還好，要喝茶嗎？
Sure.
好的
So what's going on?
怎麼了？
How come you couldn't tell me on the phone?
為什麼不能在電話上說？
Curt Golding talked to the congressman from Ohio...
柯特·戈爾丁與俄亥俄的議員談過…
And he's asked D.C.S. for an investigation by the state commission.
他要求兒童服務部門由州政府展開調查
What does that mean?
什麼意思？
It means the transfer's suspended...
這意味著移交暫停了…
And the commission can reverse the judge's decision- permanently.
調查結果可以永久廢止法官的決定
That's great! Oh, sweetheart!
太棒了！噢，寶貝！
See? I knew something would give.
你瞧？我就知道要發生什麼
I knew something would give.
我就知道一定會發生什麼
Um, listen, Jack and I were talking...
聽著，傑克和我正在談…
And we think we want to go to Haiti with you.
我們覺得我們要和你們一起去海地
Really?
真的？
Yeah. I mean, with everything that's gone on...
是的，我是說，以現在的情況…
I think it would be great for alI of us to get away, be together as a family.
我們一起，一家人在一起出去一趟，一定很棒
So, what do you think?
你覺得怎麼樣？
And it's okay to take him out of the country?
帶他出國沒關係嗎？
- You're allowed? - Of course it is.
- 你可以嗎？ - 當然可以
The order's suspended. We can do what we want.
移交令暫停了，我們做什麼都行
Besides, I think it'd be fun, you know, for the kids, for us.
而且，我覺得一定很好玩，孩子也好，大人也好
Do you think you can arrange it with the church?
你覺得我們可以和教會安排一下嗎？
It's a little last-minute, but-but absolutely.
就是時間有點緊張，不過絕對沒問題
- We'll work it out. - Okay.
- 我們會有辦法的 - 好的
- Good to see you. - Hi. Good.
- 見到你很高興 - 很好
We'll see you inside.
等會堶惆
Hey. Hi there, Molly.
嘿，你好，茱莉
It's Joey. You see him?
是喬伊，你看他？
Joey!
喬伊！
Wow. Hey, Jack.
嘿，傑克
Hey.
嘿
- It's good to see you, sir. - Nice to be back.
- 很高興見到你，先生 - 很高興回來
- It's good to see you. - You too.
- 很高興見到你 - 我也是
# The Lord bless you #
# 願天主祝福你 #
# And keep you #
# 保護你 #
# The Lord lift his countenance upon you #
# 願耶和華向你仰臉 #
# And give you peace #
# 賜你平安 #
# The Lord make his face #
# 願天主的慈顏 #
# To shine upon you #
# 光照你 #
# the Lord be gracious #
# 願主仁慈待你 #
# Gracious unto you #
# 仁慈待你 #
# Amen #
# 阿門 #
Who is it?
是誰？
It's Allyson Bower, Mrs. Porter.
我是阿里森·鮑爾，波特太太
I know it's late, but I need to speak with you.
我知道很晚了，可是我要和你談談
I知 sorry. I can't come to the door right now.
很抱歉，我現在不方便開門
Mrs. Porter, you haven't returned my calls.
波特太太，你一直沒回我電話
I need to speak with you just for a moment.
我要和你談談，只一小會
Please, open the door.
請把門打開
Mrs. Porter?
波特太太？
Something's going on with Jack and Molly.
傑克和莫莉他們有點事情
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
She says the congressman is helping her.
她說有個議員在幫助她
But I know her.
但我瞭解她
And the way she's acting, there's just something that's not right.
她的言行舉止，我覺得有點不對勁
- How should she be acting? - Think about it.
- 她應該什麼舉止？ - 想想看
Suddenly she's going to church with us...
她突然要和我們去教堂…
And now they want to leave the country and go to Haiti.
現在又要和我們去海地
Don't you think it's strange?
你不覺得有點怪嗎？
No, I don't think it's strange. We invited them, remember?
不，我不覺得怪，我們邀請過他們，記得嗎？
You know what I mean.
你知道我什麼意思
Honey, you need to be careful.
寶貝，你要小心點
I appreciate you taking my call.
謝謝你接我的電話
I just wanted to thank you personally.
我只是想親自跟你道謝
Excuse me?
你說什麼？
I just wanted to thank you for what you're doing-
我只是想為你做的事情向你道謝…
for Joey, for their son.
為了喬伊，為了他們的兒子
Ms. Norton, I told Jack weeks ago there was nothing I could do...
諾頓女士，我幾周前就告訴傑克，我沒辦法…
And there is still nothing I can do.
現在仍然沒有辦法
I'm very sorry for his situation...
對於他的情況，我很抱歉…
But I really don't appreciate this phone call.
不過我不太希望你打電話來
- I'm- I'm sorry, Congressman. I must have misunderstood. -It's alright
- 我…我很抱歉，議員先生，一定是我誤會了 - 沒關係
- I'm sorry. I didn't mean to- - That's fine.
- 我很抱歉，我不是故意要…
- Have a good day - Thank you.
- 祝您愉快 - 謝謝
Are you my real dad?
你是我真正的爸爸嗎？
Well.
好吧
Let me ask you.
我來問你
What do you think?
你覺得呢？
I think you are.
我覺得你是
Why?
為什麼
You take care of me...
你照顧我…
And you taught me how to play baseball.
你教我打棒球
And I changed your diapers too. That was gross.
我還幫你換尿布呢，真髒啊
What else? What else do I do, son?
還有什麼？我還做了什麼，兒子？
You love me.
你愛我
Yeah.
是的
And that's the most important thing a father can do.
對一個父親來說，這是最重要的
So why did Rip say he was my dad?
為什麼理普說他是我爸爸？
Listen to me for a second, Joe, okay? This might be a little confusing.
聽我說，喬，你可能不太能懂
But I'm gonna try to explain something to you, all right?
不過我還是盡量跟你講，好嗎？
Wendy is the woman that gave birth to you, okay?
溫蒂是生育你的人，懂嗎？
And then your mother and I met you...
然後你媽媽和我見到了你…
And we loved you so much that we became your real parents-forever.
我們如此愛你，我們就成了你永遠的父母
Just like Robbie Elwood?
就像羅比·艾爾伍德？
That's right. That's right. We adopted you, son.
沒錯，是的，我們收養了你，兒子
So I'm gonna stay here with you and Mom?
那我會留下來和你和媽媽在一起嗎？
Is that what you want?
你想留下來嗎？
It is?
是嗎？
Okay.
好吧
Then we'll be together, no matter what. All right?
那我們就在一起，不管發生什麼，好嗎？
No matter what.
不管發生什麼
- That's it. - Thanks, babe.
- 就這些 - 謝謝，寶貝
Ladies and gentlemen...
女生們，先生們…
Flight 56 is now ready for boarding.
56次航班準備登機
We'd like to be in first-class and gold card members...
頭等艙乘客和金卡會員…
to board Flight 56, thank you.
請現在登機，謝謝
Okay.
好了
- Put your seat belt on? That's good. - Yeah.
- 繫上安全帶，很好 - 是的
Turn around and buckle up.
轉過來扣安全帶
Ladies and gentlemen, the boarding door has been closed
女生們先生們，機艙門已經關閉
Once again, this is Flight 257 with nonstop service to Port-au-Prince.
重複一遍，這是257次航班，直飛太子港
Before the aircraft moves, all passengers must be seated..
飛機起動之前，所有乘客請坐好…
With your seat belts securely fastened tray stations stowed and baggage secured
繫好安全帶，小桌板收起，行李安放好
Enjoy your fight
祝您飛行愉快
Hey, friend, come with me. Let me show you your quarters.
嘿，朋友，跟我來，讓我帶你看看你的宿舍1
You get any of that on the fence?
你們就是這麼刷護欄的？
Hey, easy now.
嘿，你慢點
We were working hard manual labor while you boys were in town shopping.
我們在辛勤勞動，你們幾個小子卻在鎮媮坁
- Believe me, you were better off here. - Bill, you mind taking over?
- 相信我，你最好還是呆在這兒 - 比爾，你能替她一下嗎？
- Oh, yeah, with pleasure. Can I do that? - Oh, gladly.
- 噢是的，很榮幸，我能做那個嗎？ - 噢，太好了
I値l go get cleaned up.
我去梳洗一下
Hey.
嘿
So, I found a taxi driver to pick us up tomorrow at 2:00 p. m.
我找到一個出租車司機明天下午兩點來接我們
And our flight's at 4:30.
我們的航班是4:30
Okay. Do you think he'll show?
好的，你認為他會出現嗎？
Yeah. I gave him a hundred dollars today...
是的，我今天給了他一百美元…
And I said I'd give him $200 tomorrow when he gets us to the airport.
我說明天他把我們送到機場後，我再給他二百美元
Trust me. That's a lot of money for a guy like that. He'll show.
相信我，對那種人這是一大筆錢，他會出現的
You're home early.
你提前回家了
Yeah.
是的
They sent me home.
他們要我回家
I can't concentrate, and I-
我無法集中，我…
I can't eat and I can't sleep.
我吃不下，睡不著
And I don't understand why you- you haven't called the police.
我不明白你為什麼還不叫警察
No police.
不要警察
So you're leaving me then.
你要離開我了
No.
不
I don't think so.
我不這麼想
Rip.
理普
We've both made big mistakes in our lives.
我們在生活中都犯下大錯
But I know your heart.
可我瞭解你的內心
I know, inside, you're good...
我知道，你的內心，你是好人…
Even if you don't.
哪怕你自己不這麼想
I知 sorry.
我很抱歉
I知 so sorry.
我真的很抱歉
Sorry.
抱歉
I know.
我知道
Now, if we're going to try...
現在，如果我們想要…
There's one thing I-I need.
還有一個東西，我要…
You remember?
你記得嗎？
Father Logan.
洛根神父
We'll do it together, babe.
我們共同面對，寶貝
Me and you.
你和我一起
Tackle him.
撲倒他
Okay.
好
Oh, my gosh!
噢，天吶
I'm exhausted.
我累死了
Nice job, man.
不錯，夥計
Nice, man. That's what I like to see.
不錯，夥計，我就想看到這樣
I値l meet you guys at the bus at noon, and then we'll head into town with everybody else?
我們中午在巴士上見，然後我們和其他人一起去鎮上？
Actually, we were thinking about hanging as a family and letting you guys do your thing.
其實，我在想應該家人待在一起，你們還有你們的事情
We'll come back and have dinner with you later, if you don't mind.
我們晚點回來和你們吃晚飯，如果你們覺得可以的話
- It's good by me. Yeah. - Yeah?
- 我沒問題，可以 - 是嗎？
- It's good. - Okay. You sure?
- 很好 - 好吧，你確定？
Yeah. Is that okay?
是的，可以嗎？
Yeah, of course. Whatever you want.
是的，當然，怎麼都可以
Okay.
好吧
See you at dinner. I love you.
晚餐見，我愛你
- I love you. - I love you too.
- 我愛你 - 我也愛你
Okay.
好吧
- See you later? - Yeah, man. Have fun. Joey.
- 待會見？ - 是的，夥計，好好玩，喬伊
You guys have a good day.
祝你們愉快
- Bye. - Bye, Joey.
- 再見 - 再見，喬伊
- He's a ballplayer, huh? - Yeah, he is.
- 他是打球好手，嗯？ - 是的
- See you tonight. - All right, Jack.
- 晚上見 - 好的，傑克
Are you hot? Your cheeks are all pink.
你熱嗎？你的臉都紅了
- Come on, buddy. - See you guys.
- 來吧，夥計 - 再見
Are you okay?
你沒事吧？
Come here.
過來
Molly lied.
莫莉撒謊了
Curt Golding isn't helping them.
柯特·戈爾丁沒幫他們
They used us, Bill.
他們利用了我們，比爾
They used the church, this trip.
他們利用了教會和這次旅行
They're taking Joey, and they're running away.
他們帶著喬伊要逃走
I know.
我知道
What? What do you mean you know?
什麼？你知道是什麼意思？
It's what I would have done.
我也會這麼做的
No, Bill. No, it's wrong, and you know it's wrong.
不，比爾，這是錯的，你知道這樣不對
- If God wanted them to have Joey- - Beth, stop it! Stop it!
- 如果上帝要他們得到喬伊… - 貝絲，住嘴，住嘴！
You don't get to decide what God's will is.
上帝的意志不是你說了算的
Do you want Joey to be beaten, maybe killed by this man?
你想要喬伊被這個人打，也許被打死嗎？
No.
不
The courts are wrong, Beth.
法庭的決定是錯誤的，貝絲
What other option do they have at this point?
現在這樣，他們還有選擇嗎？
Honey, what else is this trip for if not to save children?
親愛的，這次旅程的目的不就是要幫助孩子嗎？
Right?
對吧？
I know you're gonna miss your sister.
我知道你會想念你的姐姐
But this isn't your choice. We have to let them go.
但這不是你能決定的，我們只能讓他們走
Everything's gonna be okay.
一切都會好的
No, it's not.
不，不會的
Why?
為什麼？
I called Allyson Bower.
我給阿里森·鮑爾打了電話
Oh, Beth.
噢，貝絲
All right, here we go. Line up. Line up.
好吧，我們開始，站好，站好
Defense, you're getting burned.
防守隊，你們完了
- Jack. - What?
- 傑克 - 怎麼了？
You need to get your family out of here right now.
你們一家人要馬上離開這
- What? What are you talking about? - Now.
- 什麼？你在說什麼？ - 馬上
- Bill, what's going on? - I'm so sorry, sweetheart.
- 比爾，怎麼回事？ - 我很抱歉，親愛的
- What? - Dad, is everything okay?
- 怎麼了？ - 爸爸，沒事吧？
Let's go. Let's go.
我們走，我們走
Walk, walk, walk.
我們走，我們走，走，走，走
Give me the keys. Give me the keys to the jeep.
把鑰匙給我，把車鑰匙給我
Jack. Jack. Here you go. Take the jeep.
傑克，傑克，給你，把車拿走
Where to? Where to?
去哪？去哪？
I got you covered. Go, go, go.
我來掩護你們，快走
- What did you do? - I don't know.
- 你做什麼了？ - 我不知道
What did you do?
你做了什麼了？
Sit on your mom's lap.
坐在你媽媽腿上
Come here, baby. Come here.
過來，寶貝，過來
Just relax, sweetheart. Just relax.
別緊張，寶貝，放鬆
Mommy, where are we going?
媽咪，我們要去哪？
It's okay, baby. Just breathe.
沒事的，寶貝，保持呼吸
At the gate, we'll just go nice and easy, all right?
到了大門，我們要放鬆，好嗎？
- How are you, sir? - How you doing, man?
- 你好啊，先生 - 你好，夥計
- Where you going? - We're just going shopping.
- 你們去哪？ - 我們去買東西
That's okay. That's okay.
可以，可以
- Everything's okay? - Perfect.
- 一切還好吧？ - 好極了
Good.
很好
Thanks a lot.
多謝了
Okay! Stop! Get out of your car!
停下！下車！
- Easy, man. - Mommy?
- 放鬆，夥計 - 媽咪？
Right now.
馬上下車
Jack.
傑克
Mr. and Mrs. Campbell.
坎貝爾先生和太太
Where is our son?
我們的兒子在哪？
I知 sorry that you had to be brought back this way...
很抱歉用這種辦法把你們帶回來…
But I had to stop you from making a very big mistake.
可我必須防止你們鑄成大錯
- Is Joey all right? - He's fine.
- 喬伊沒事吧？ - 他很好
- He's just down the hall. - Ms. Bower, we've done nothing wrong.
- 他就在大廳 - 鮑爾太太，我們沒做錯什麼
Mr. Campbell, please, have a seat.
坎貝爾先生，請坐下
Now, you did do something wrong. We both know that.
你們確實做錯了，我們大家都清楚
And I've spent a lot of hours trying to keep you out of jail.
我花費了好多時間才讓你們沒坐牢
I壇 like to talk to my lawyer.
我要找我的律師談
Mr. Campbell, I am on your side.
坎貝爾先生，我站在你這邊
I am.
真的
Now, it's been a really long night for all of us.
我們都度過一個漫長的夜晚
I have Mrs. Porter with me. She's right outside.
波特太太也來了，她就在外面
She wants to talk to you...
她想和你們談談…
So I'm gonna bring her in.
我帶她進來
Hello.
你們好
I知 Wendy Porter.
我是溫蒂·波特
I know you tried to run away with Joey.
我知道你們想帶喬伊逃走
Ms. Porter...
波特太太…
He had bruises on his body.
他的身上有瘀傷
I was just trying to protect my son.
我只是想保護我的兒子
I have to telI you, when you...
我要告訴你們，當你…
Offered my husband money for Joey...
用錢向我丈夫交換喬伊的時候…
You nearly crushed the man.
你差點讓這個人崩潰
Would that be what you would teach our son? That-
你想這樣教我們的兒子嗎？
That poor people can just be bought off?
窮人就可以被收買嗎？
No.
不
I thought he wanted money.
我以為他要錢
And I- I was wrong.
我…我錯了
And I know that now.
我現在知道了
You have no idea how much that boy means to him.
你不知道那孩子對他意味著什麼
I made a terrible mistake seven years ago.
七年前我犯下大錯
I never should have given up my baby.
我不該放棄我的寶貝
But with everything that's happened...
可經過了這些事情…
I need to be sure now that I'm doing the right thing for him.
我要確保我的決定對他來說是正確的
Mrs. Porter.
波特太太
Wendy.
溫蒂
Joey is our whole world.
喬伊是我們的全部
He's our boy.
他是我們的兒子
I love him as if I gave birth to him myself.
我愛他一如我親生一般
And I can't imagine spending a day without him.
我無法一天沒有他
But from the moment we brought him home...
從我們帶他回家那一刻開始…
My biggest fear was that he would wake up one morning...
我最害怕的就是有一天他醒來…
And realize that I'm not really his mother...
突然意識到我不是他的真正母親…
That I'm...
我只是…
Just some woman who's raising him.
只是把他養大的人
But he never did.
可他沒有
And he never will.
他以後也不會
Ms. Bower.
鮑爾太太
I have the revised adoption papers here.
我這兒有重新領養的文件
Mr. Porter has already signed...
波特先生已經簽了字…
And I personally witnessed his signature.
我親自見證了他簽字
Thank you.
謝謝你
Thank you so much.
非常感謝
I want you both to know that, uh...
我要你們兩人知道…
Rip really does love Joey.
理普真的很愛喬伊
He just wasn't ready to be a father, and he knows that.
他只是還沒準備好做一個父親，他自己也知道
Ms. Porter...
波特太太…
Will you tell your husband that I apologize?
轉告你丈夫，我向他道歉
Is there anything that we can do for you?
有沒有什麼我能為他做的？
And it doesn't have to be money.
不一定是錢
I mean, I-
我是說，我…
We'll be all right. We're getting help. Thanks.
我們會沒事的，有人幫助我們，多謝了
There is one thing that- that you could do for me.
還有一件事，你們可以幫我
I would like Joey to know that he- he has two mothers-
我想讓喬伊知道，他有兩個母親…
one that loved him so much that she couldn't let him go...
一個如此愛他，不能放他走…
And one that loved him so much that she had to.
一個如此愛他，不得不放他走
You have my word.
我向你保證
Thank you.
謝謝你
May I- May I say good-bye to him?
我能…我能向他道別嗎？
Of course.
當然
Joey, it was real nice...
喬伊，真的很高興…
Having you come and spend time with us at our house.
你能來我們家，和我們住了一段時間
Getting to know you...
讓我們瞭解你…
And see what a bright and beautiful boy you've become...
看到你變成了一個聰明、漂亮的男孩
Laughing with you and
和你一起歡笑
have honestly been some of the happiest moments of my life.
那些時光真的是我們一輩子最快樂的時候
What happened to your face?
你的臉怎麼了？
Oh, I got hurt, but I'm gonna be okay.
我受傷了，不過我會沒事的
Am I gonna come see you again?
我還能見到你嗎？
No. No, sweetheart. That was our last visit.
不，甜心，上次是最後一次了
You're not coming back anymore.
你不會再來了
Why not?
為什麼？
Remember I told you about the dandelion...
還記得我跟你說過蒲公英…
And how we had to set the wish free?
我們要放飛我們的希望嗎？
Sometimes people are like that too, baby.
有時候人也是這樣的，寶貝
Now...
現在…
I want you to remember me...
我想要你記住我…
And try and remember...
盡量去記住…
Only the happy times, okay?
那些快樂的時光，好嗎？
This here... is very special.
這個…很特別
Rip gave it to me when I was a girl, and...
在我還是女孩的時候，理普給我的…
I want you to have it.
我把它給你
Inside is a picture of me and Rip...
堶惘釦琠M理普的照片…
And our address in case you should ever need anything...
還有我們的地址，萬一你需要什麼…
Anything at all.
什麼都可以
Maybe one day when you're a big, strong man...
也許有一天，你會長成一個強壯的大人…
We'll meet again.
我們會再見的
I love you.
我愛你
This is the final boarding call-
最後一次登機廣播
Mommy! Daddy!
媽媽！爸爸！
- Hey. - Hey!
- 嘿
Oh! Oh, we missed you.
噢，我們好想你
- Me too. - Yeah, you okay?
- 我也是 - 你還好吧？
- You sure? - Yeah.
- 真的嗎？ - 是的
Okay, good.
很好
Come here, Son. You ready?
過來，兒子，準備好了嗎？
Now, hold on tight, okay? All right.
抓緊了，好嗎？
- Can you steer it? - Yeah.
- 你能掌舵嗎？ - 是的
Feels great.
太棒了
You stay right there.
你抓穩了
- Is it fun? - Yeah!
- 好玩嗎？ - 是的
Good job.
不錯
You're all right. Just hold it right there.
你做得不錯，抓穩了
We're gonna crash.
我們要撞了
There's no boats in front of you. I'm watching out for you.
你前面沒船，我幫你看著呢